- Gizem Ayaz Yegül -

Full-Stack Web Developer - Experienced Product Owner and Scrum Master

Berlin, Germany • +491723016662 • gizemayazyegul@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/gayazyegul/ • gizemayaz.com • Github • Available to start immediately, You can reach via phone or mail, 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. | Mon-Fri

Summary

A certified Meta Front End Developer and currently finished Full-Stack Web Developer BootCamp at Ironhack. With an experience as a Scrum Master/Product Owner, possess a unique blend of knowledge and project management skills that are specifically designed for Web Development. Through engaging web development and incorporating feedback, gained skills to create web applications that are both user-friendly and visually appealing. Having a passion in working collaboratively with teams to push the boundaries of software development.

Skills

Hard Skills

- HTML CSS Javascript Typescript React Bootstrap Express.JS Git RESTful API Postman SQL
- MongoDB JIRA Agile Scrum Kanban User Story Acceptance Criteria

Soft Skills

• Collaboration • Adaptability • Proactivity • Problem-Solving • Mentoring • Teamwork • Time Management

Professional Experience

Usertesting.com, Berlin/Germany • Freelancer Tester

May 2021 - Present

- Gained valuable insights into optimizing user experience, interface design, and overall functionality of websites and mobile apps. Earned an outstanding feedback score of 4.8/5, reflecting a 96% positive user satisfaction rate.
- Applied feedback to improve comprehension of user needs and preferences for more intuitive and user-friendly applications.

Alocai(Altagram), Berlin/Germany • Product Owner

December 2020 - May 2021

- Shaped and executed the product roadmap, organized team workflows, and led agile ceremonies for successful objective attainment. Achieved 90% of planned milestones on the product roadmap.
- Demonstrated ease with technical aspects, combining technical proficiency with Agile knowledge.
 Reduced lead times by 20% through optimized team workflows.
- Introduced a game-changing 'Instant Quote' feature through benchmarking and collaboration with a UX designer, optimizing user experience. Achieved a 20% increase in landing the page since the introduction of the 'Instant Quote' feature.
- Executed multiple beta launches, showcasing effective project management with developers and QA engineer.

- Led high-value projects, including the development of the easy return center contributing to a 15% reduction in return-related customer issues., checkout page revision achieved a 25% decrease in cart abandonment rates and basket page revision increased average order value by 18% through strategic improvements on the basket page.
- Actively participated in requirement gathering meetings with diverse stakeholders, ensuring a deep understanding of challenges and contributing meaningful solutions to the platform and customer experience.
- Enhanced efficiency by 30% in requirement gathering meetings, resulting in quicker decision-making.
- Played a key role in the agile transformation, serving as a Scrum Master and actively contributing to estimation, prioritization, and backlog management.
- Increased backlog turnover by 25% through effective prioritization and management.

Akbank, Istanbul/Turkey • Banking Analytics Intern

August 2017 - September 2017

- Identified opportunities to enhance data analysis efficiency by analyzing ATM withdrawal statistics. Applied Excel tools such as VLOOKUP and Pivot Table, resulting in a 20% reduction in data extraction and cleaning time.
- Collaborated with two data analysts and managers to optimize processes related to ATM withdrawal data analysis. Implemented streamlined workflows, leading to a 15% improvement in overall process efficiency.

Education

Physics Engineering • Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul/Turkey September 2011 - September 2017

While Istanbul Technical University entered the top 10 worldwide in two fields according to THE 2023 Impact Ranking, which covers the Sustainable Development Goals, it once again proved that it is among the most prestigious universities in the world, ranking 58th in the general ranking covering all fields.

- Coursework in Python, C++, and Data Analyses
- Thesis: Parallel Programming in Fortran
- Member of Physics Engineering Club
- Member of Dance Club

Certification & Languages

Full-Stack Web Development • Ironhack / Berlin, Germany

October 2023 - December 2023

Meta Frontend Development • Coursera / Berlin, Germany

April 2023

Professional Scrum Master • Scrum.org

April 2019

• English C1 • German TELC C1 • Turkish C2